Arif Mollick

+91-8515068850 | LinkedIn/GitHub: arifmollick8578 | arifmollick8578@gmail.com | Kolkata, West Bengal

Summary

Software Engineer around **3.5+ years of experience on Android development (including Google project)**. Strong problem-solving skills with a track record of addressing complex technical issues. Thrives on challenges and enjoys working in fast-paced environments. Flexible and eager to contribute to meaningful projects while continuously learning and growing. Seeking a role that offers opportunities for professional development and the chance to make a significant impact.

Experience

Walmart Global Tech | Chennai, Tamil Nadu

Software Engineer - III (Android) | 01/2024 - Present

- Completed necessary trainings and contributing on Checkout and Transactions modules on Walmart android application

Tech stack: GraphQL · Android

<u>American Reprographics Company (ARC) Document Solutions | Kolkata, West Bengal</u> Software Engineer (Android) | 07/2023 – 01/2024

- Worked on <u>ARC Facilities</u> android application, which provides instant access to your critical facilities information right from your android mobile device
- Dedicatedly worked on restructuring the tag/pin flow for the application with latest tech using MVVM, Pagination, Offline support with Room DB, File upload on AWS, Camera, ML-Kit etc. performed CRUD operation to the tag without duplicate
- Started working on latest "ARC Facilities 2.0" app using newly market ready Jetpack Compose from scratch

Tech stack: Data Binding · Android ML Kit · Jetpack Compose · Retrofit · Room DB · Paging3 · Java · Kotlin · Coroutine · Flows Raja Software Labs | Google India, Bangalore (On-site)

- Android Developer | 06/2021 07/23
- Worked on <u>Google Home Application</u> (Android) that enables users to set up, manage and control home products including camera, thermostat, light, speaker, Wi-Fi and Nest products
- Worked on feature requests, tasks, KPIs (Key Performance Indicators) and high priority bugs
- Delivered end to end impactful features for camera device (combining streaming, history events, saving clips, and other functions in the same screen for easy access)
- Developed multiple Activity, Fragment, DialogFragment, Coroutine, Custom view components (RadialView, Slider, Seekbar, BottomSheets), Data fetching and Streaming, Flows, Deeplink, Hilt and Analytics widely

Tech stack: Kotlin · XML · Java · Retrofit · Coroutines · Firebase · Gitlab · Native Android Development · Model-View-Viewmodel (MVVM) · Dagger · Hilt · Mockito · Flows · Protobuf

IIT, Patna | Patna, Bihar

Research Intern | 05/2019 - 07/2019

- First industry level machine learning project "Classification of Texts from Twitter data" which categorizes tweets by their contents into Business, Sports, Entertainments, Politics, Education and Technology
- Divided data into test and train data and used Gensim to convert tweet content and title into vectors
- Training data using CNN, Attention mechanism and Bi-LSTM models resulted in 99.6% accuracy

Tech stack: Keras · TensorFlow · FastText by Facebook · Gensim · Deep Learning · CNN

Project

CryptoWikiApp Using Jetpack Compose

- CryptoWikiApp is an Android application that displays a list of cryptocurrency coins with details about their name, symbol, ranking and active status on the home screen. On click of any coin, further details appear with category/tag, team members (Founder, Blockchain developer), logo and learn more link redirected to documentation
- Cryptocurrency data fetched via REST API call from Coinpaprika used Retrofit and Coroutine for optimize
- Implemented dependency injection using Hilt to provide objects of APIs or DB instances
- Fetched REST API data through Retrofit and handled all statuses
- Followed Android clean architecture and standard project design and structure

Tech used: Android Jetpack Compose · Kotlin · Java · MVI Architecture · Coroutine · Retrofit · REST · SharedPreferences · Clean Architecture · Composable

Technical Skills

Android · Java · Kotlin · Firebase · RxJava · Retrofit · Dagger · Hilt · Coroutine · MVVM · Unit Testing · Espresso · Roboelectric · Junit · Github · Data Structure and Algorithms · SQL · SDLC · Spring boot · Python · Flutter & Dart

Certifications & Achievements

Rank 90 at CodeVita season 8, 2019 (India-zone1) · Store Listing Certificate by Google Play · LinkedIn Skill Assessment Badge on "Kotlin" and "Android" · HackerRank Certified Programmer · Elitmus score: 88.43

Education